

CONTACT

- +39 340 9310 562
- Via Moneta 50, Milan (IT)
- 8 live:federico.decillia
- federicodecillia.github.io

EDUCATION

M.S IN BUSINESS STATISTICS

University of Padova (2012 - 2014)

B.S IN BUSINESS STATISTICS

University of Padova (2008 - 2011)

LLP ERASMUS (BARCELONA)

University Pompeu Fabra (2012)

ICT HIGH-SCHOOL DIPLOMA

I.T.I. Severi, Padua (2003 - 2008)

EXPERTISE

Python, R	••••
Git	••••
Office, GSuite, iWork	••••
BI (Tableau, Spotfire)	••••
SQL	••••
SAS, SPSS	••••
KNime	••••
Spark	•••00
Azure, AWS, GCP	••••
CI/CD	••••
Airflow	••000
Docker	••000

FEDERICO DE CILLIA

Lead Data Scientist - R&D, Retail, Market Analyis, Media

ABOUT ME

Senior Data Scientist specialized in Big-Data analytics, Machine Learning, Time Series modeling, Automation & RPA, BI & Data Visualization.

Demonstrated history of strong innovation attitude, leading the change of international Data Science organizations to new tools and methodologies.

Proven track record of leading strategic analytics projects, from ideation to production of ML pipelines, RPA & BI solutions, using programming languages (Python, R, SQL, Spark), Data Visualization tools (MS Power BI, Spotfire, Google Data Studio, Tableau, SAS VA), locally & in-cloud (Azure, AWS, GCP), exploiting Agile & Software development tools (Git, CI/CD, Airflow, Docker).

EXPERIENCE

Lead Data Scientist - Retail Optimization, Luxottica | 02/2021 - present Retail Optimization Planning Leader

Senior Data Scientist, Nielsen | 09/2017 - 02/2021

Lead many international projects (with up to 10 people per project) to implement scalable, automated Machine Learning (Classification, Regression, Clustering, Time Series) in multiple countries. Direct exposure to management & clients presenting business insights & analyses. Chair of Italian Diversity & Inclusion Team

Data Scientist Consultant, Bip (@ Sky Italy) | 04/2016 - 09/2017
Developed and implemented a NLP Churn-Prediction project & Text-Mining analyses, used to improve Retention/Upselling/Downgrade Marketing strategies.

Data Science Business Consultant, Value Lab | 09/2015 - 04/2016

SAS Masterclass Big Data, SAS Institute | 06/2015 - 09/2015

Data Mining Junior, Bocconi Alumni Association | 02/2015 - 06/2015

Tutor for exchange students, University of Padua | 2012 - 2014

LANGUAGE SKILLS ATTITUDES & INTERESTS

Italian: Mother tongueDriver of Innovation, Leader of changeEnglish: Proficient (C1)Communicator with Storytelling skillSpanish: Upper-Intermediate (B2)D&I and Sustainability advocate

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Al for everyone, Deeplearning.ai. on Coursera	12/2020
Machine Learning Specialization, University of Washington	01/2020
Deep Learning Specialization, Deeplearning.ai. on Coursera	06/2019
Complete Git & Github Masterclass, O'Reilly	10/2018
Data Science and ML with Python and Spark, O'Reilly	06/2018
Python for Data Science, University of California San Diego	12/2017
Intro & Intermediate Python for Data Science, Datacamp	09/2017
Text Mining and Analytics, University of Illinois	05/2017
ML for Data Science and Analytics, Columbia University	01/2017
Tackling the challenges of Big Data, MIT	09/2016
SAS Programming - Macro Language - SQL, SAS Institute	09/2015